Guide to the Olga Rudge Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1904-89; Series IX; 3.5; (7 boxes)
  - ALBUMS
    - "Capri 1921" (includes Olga Rudge, Renata Borgatti, Maria Favai, Lindy Shaw-Paige, and others), 1921, n.d. (Box 148, Folder 3467)
    - "Album 2"( Olga Rudge, Ezra Pound, Mary de Rachewiltz), [1926-35?] (Box 148, Folder 3468-77)
  - EZRA POUND
    - Ezra Pound alone, 1904-68 (Box 148, Folder 3478-89)
      See also: Oversize, Box 160, folder 3735
    - Ezra Pound alone, 1969-72, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 3490-96)
    - Portraits by Bast, [1971]
      See: Oversize, box 161, folder 3736
    - Ezra Pound with Olga Rudge, 1923-72 (Box 149, Folder 3497-3500)
      See also: Oversize, Box 161, folder 3737
    - Ezra Pound with Olga Rudge and others, [1930?]-72, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 3501-06)
    - Ezra Pound with family, 1927-71, n.d. (Box 150, Folder 3507-08)
    - Ezra Pound with others, 1930-72, n.d. (Box 150, Folder 3509-24)
      See also: Oversize, Box 161, folder 3738
  - OLGA RUDGE
    - Olga Rudge alone, 1897-1958, n.d. (Box 150, Folder 3525-30)
      See also: Oversize, Box 161, folder 3739
    - Olga Rudge alone, 1960-87, n.d. (Box 151, Folder 3531-32)
    - Olga Rudge with others, 1918-88, n.d. (Box 151, Folder 3533-43)
      See also: Oversize, Box 161, folder 3740
  - OTHER PERSONS
    - Antheil, George (inscribed to Olga Rudge), n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 161, folder 3741
    - Bardi, P. M., n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3544)
    - Barilli, Bruno, n.d.
    - Barriera, M., n.d.
    - Borgatti, Renata, 1921, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3545)
    - Brass, Italico, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3546)
    - Brooks, Romaine, 1921
    - Carpanini, Ferdinando, 1967, 1972
    - Casella, Yvonne (inscribed to Olga Rudge), 1921 Sep (Box 152, Folder 3547)
    - Cecil, Winifred, n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 161, folder 3741
    - Chigi-Saracini, Guido, conte, 1960, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3548)
    - Chiovenda Petrucci, Annetta, 1956, 1988
    - Cookson, William, and family (Box 152, Folder 3549)
    - Cooper, Vincent, n.d.
    - Dalliba-John, Kate (Ramooth), n.d.
    - Drummond, Fifi (Box 152, Folder 3550)
    - Enesco, Georges, 1951
    - Favai, Gennaro, n.d.
    - Harte, Ethel Bret, n.d.
    - Hughes, Robert, 1983 (Box 152, Folder 3551)
    - Insall, John Gilbert Stuart, 1917 Jul
    - Leukovicz, Hneri, n.d.
    - Malanga, Gerard, n.d.
    - Moore, Marianne, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3552)
    - Mussolini, Benito (inscribed to Olga Rudge), 1933 Jan
    - Mussolini, Benito, n.d.
    - [Nocher], Graziella, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3553)
    - Noguchi, Isamu, 1967 Mar
    - Pescetto, Alberto, 1958
    - Pizzetti, Ildebrando (inscribed to Olga Rudge), 1918-56
    - Pound, Dorothy (Box 152, Folder 3554)
    - [Pound, Homer?]
    - Rachewiltz, Boris de and Patrizia (Box 152, Folder 3555)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1928-78, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3556-58)
      See also: Oversize, Box 161, folder 3741
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de, with others, 1985-88, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3559-60)
    - Rachewiltz, Walter de, and family, 1952-89, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3561-62)
    - Reid, Ethel, 1980? (Box 152, Folder 3563)
    - Richards, Kathleen, 1919
    - Scheiwiller, Vanni, 1948, 1961 (Box 152, Folder 3564)
    - Segovia, Andrés, with Adlai Stevenson
    - Singh, G., 1977, 1982
    - Sokh[ard], Corso, 1952
    - Solane, Dominique, [1966 Nov] (Box 152, Folder 3565)
    - Solane, Janine, n.d.
    - Tomita, P. Toyoji, 1983 Mar 28
    - Vannini, Armando, 1956 Nov 3
    - Vroom, Patrizia de Rachewiltz de, with family, 1982-88, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3566-68)
    - Wang, Mrs. Lucien, 1959 (Box 152, Folder 3569)
    - Wilamowitz-Möllendorf, Prof.
    - Unidentified children, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3570-71)
    - Unidentified men, 1981-83, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3572-73)
    - Unidentified women, 1950-75, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3574-75)
    - Unidentified groups, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3576-77)
  - PLACES
    - Hailey, Idaho: Ezra Pound's birthplace, 1973 Oct (Box 153, Folder 3578)
    - Hamilton College: the library, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3579)
    - Ipplis, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3580)
    - London, 1965 Dec, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3581)
    - Madrid: Monastery of S. Lorenzo, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3582)
    - Rapallo: grave of Homer Pound (Box 153, Folder 3583)
    - San Michele, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3584)
    - Siena
      - Castelnuovo Bearardenga, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3585)
      - Palazzo Chigi-Saracini, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3586)
      - Teatro dei Rinovati, 1950 Sep 20 (Box 153, Folder 3587)
    - Venice
      - General, 1975-84, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3588)
      - Grave of Ezra Pound, 1974, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3589)
      - 252 Calle Querini, 1987, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3590-92)
    - Victoria, B.C., 1964, 1970 (Box 153, Folder 3593)
    - Unidentified places, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3594-3619)
  - MISCELLANEOUS PHOTOS
    - Airplanes, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3620)
    - Artwork
      - Portraits of Ezra Pound (paintings, busts, sketches) (Box 154, Folder 3621-22)
        See also: Oversize, Box 161, folder 3742
      - Portrait mask of Olga Rudge, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3623)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3624-26)
        See also: Oversize, Box 162, folder 3743
    - Cats, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3627)
    - Exhibits, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3628)
    - Household objects, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3629)
    - Manuscripts, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3630-31)
    - Music, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3632-34)
    - Performances, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3635)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3636)
    - Unidentified negatives, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3637)
      See also: Oversize, Box 162, folder 3744
- Family Papers, 1887-1926; Series X; 1; (2 boxes)
  Series X, Family Papers, is composed of papers concerning members of the Rudge family arranged by type of material and then by family member. The series is housed in Boxes 155-56.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Rudge, Julia O'Connell
      - Biederman, E. J., 1888 May 18 (Box 155, Folder 3638)
      - Campbell, ?, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3639)
      - Card, W. C., 1913 Aug 11 (Box 155, Folder 3640)
      - Clermont-Janneau, Ch., 1916 Aug 2 (Box 155, Folder 3641)
      - Cummings, Helen, 1905 Jan 2 (Box 155, Folder 3642)
      - Duncan, Ethel, 1912 Aug 22 (Box 155, Folder 3643)
      - Duncan, Mabel, 1911 Jan 25 (Box 155, Folder 3644)
      - Gerard, E. A., 1910 Sep 29 (Box 155, Folder 3645)
      - Granger, Percy, 1907 Mar 7 (Box 155, Folder 3646)
      - Grey, Arthur, 1890 May 17 (Box 155, Folder 3647)
      - Leigh-Hunt, Kathleen, 1913 Jul 21 (Box 155, Folder 3648)
      - Mistral, Frederi, 1911 (Box 155, Folder 3649)
      - Rudge, Arthur, 1910-18 (Box 155, Folder 3650-53)
      - Rudge, J. Edgar, 1901 Aug 2 (Box 155, Folder 3654)
      - Rudge, Teddy, 1906-18, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3655)
      - Russell, T. Arthur, 1916 Aug 18 (Box 155, Folder 3656)
      - Sharpe, L. G., 1918 Dec 3 (Box 155, Folder 3657)
      - Sillis, W., 1919 Oct 9 (Box 155, Folder 3658)
      - Wax, Sylvia, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3659)
      - Williams, J. L., n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3660)
      - Unidentified, 1910, 1916, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3661-63)
    - Other Family Members
      - Rudge, Arthur to Teddy Rudge, 1916 Dec 4 (Box 155, Folder 3664)
      - Rudge, J. Edgar to Teddy Rudge, 1911 Jan 3 (Box 155, Folder 3665)
      - Rudge, Teddy to Hourlier, Emile, 1915 Apr 18 (Box 155, Folder 3666)
      - Rudge, Teddy to Rudge, Arthur, 1916 Dec 8 (Box 155, Folder 3667)
      - Rudge, Teddy to Santa Claus, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3668)
  - FAMILY PAPERS
    - Rudge, Arthur
      - Commission to the Royal Air Force, 1918 (Box 155, Folder 3669)
      - Menu, 1918 Mar 19 (Box 155, Folder 3670)
      - Notebook ("Chess"), n.d.
      - Officer's Record of Services, 1917-18 (Box 155, Folder 3671)
    - Rudge, Julia O'Connell
      - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3672)
      - "Delle Sedie School of Singing, Ltd.": brochure, [1907?] (Box 155, Folder 3673)
      - Laundry list (Box 155, Folder 3674)
      - Programs, 1887-1903, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3675)
      - Scrapbook and autographs, 1902-20, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3676)
    - Rudge, Teddy
      - Diaries, 1914, 1915 (Box 155, Folder 3677)
    - Miscellaneous Papers
      - Burial plot locations, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3678)
      - Transcripts of Rudge family letters from World War I
        - Manuscripts, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3679-81)
        - Typescripts, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3682)
        - Galleys, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3683)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Albums
      - Family album, ca. 1895-1920
        See: Oversize, Box 162, folders 3745-48
      - Family album (fragment), [1895-1905?] (Box 156, Folder 3684)
    - People
      - Baynes, Harold C., 1921 Nov (Box 156, Folder 3685)
      - Rudge, Arthur, [ca. 1900]-18 (Box 156, Folder 3686-87)
      - Rudge, George, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 162, folder 3745
      - Rudge, Julia O'Connell, 1916-17, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3688-90)
        See also: Oversize, Box 162, folder 3745
      - Rudge, Teddy, 1906-26, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3691-92)
      - Rudge family groups, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3693-96)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Animals and plants (pictures collected by the Rudges as children) (Box 156, Folder 3697)
- Ezra Pound Foundation (formerly restricted material), Series XI; 1; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series XI, Ezra Pound Foundation, was formerly restricted until 2016. Legally privileged documents and legal documents that by their terms were governed by confidentiality clauses have been redacted from files P: Negotiations with Yale and Q: Closing documents.
  The material in Series XI was formerly restricted until 2016. Legally privileged documents and legal documents that by their terms were governed by confidentiality clauses have been redacted from files P: Negotiations with Yale and Q: Closing documents.
  - Hahn, Loeser and Parks Files
    - General, 1986-90; 3749-3753 (Box 163)
    - A--Incorporation documents, 1986-87 (Box 163)
    - B--IRS Application, 1986-90; 3755-3756 (Box 163)
    - C--Stanford University, 1986-87 (Box 163)
    - D--Trustees Meeting, undated (Box 163)
    - E--Alan Levy Materials, 1986-87 (Box 163)
    - F--Youngstown State University, undated (Box 163)
    - G--Gabriele Stocchi, 1990 (Box 163)
    - H--Scott Lavelle, Attorney General, 1988 (Box 163)
    - I--Olga Rudge, undated (Box 163)
    - J--Olga Rudge: Paine Billing, 1986 (Box 163)
    - K--Copies of Deed and Transfers, 1988-90 (Box 163)
    - L--Ezra Pound Billing, 1987-90 (Box 163)
    - M--James Laughlin, 1988 (Box 163)
    - N--Oberlin - Pound Tapes, 1988 (Box 163)
    - O--Ohio Historical Society, 1988 (Box 163)
    - P--Negotiations with Yale, 1990, undated (Box 163)
    - Q--Closing Documents, 1990 (Box 163)
    - R--Credito Romagnolo, 1990 (Box 163)
    - S--Donald J. Carroll, 1989-90 (Box 163)
    - T--Cheryl A. Lukacs, 1990 (Box 163)
    - U--Ezra Pound Literary Trust, 1987 (Box 163)
    - V--Legal Research, 1989 (Box 163)
    - W--Foundation Archive Draft Inventory, 1990 (Box 163)
    - X--Gaudier-Brozeska [Gaudier-Brzeska], 1989, undated (Box 163)
    - Y--Ezra Pound Foundation Accounts, 1990, undated (Box 163)
  - Jane Turner Rylands Files
    - Archive, 1978-85, undated; 3780-3781 (Box 163)
    - Family Contest, 1988-90 (Box 163)
    - Foundation--General, 1986-89 (Box 163)
    - Fundraising, 1984-87 (Box 163)
    - House, 1987-88 (Box 163)
    - Library of Congress, 1987 (Box 163)
    - Projects, 1985-1988 (Box 163)
- Oversize
  Oversize material has been placed here in series order.
  - Antheil, George, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3699)
  - Franck, Arthur, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3700)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1975 Jul 2 (Box 157, Folder 3701)
  - Artwork, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3702)
  - Funeral Ribbons for Ezra Pound, 1972 Nov (Box 157, Folder 3703)
  - "Lettre di Antonio Vivaldi": The Listener, p. 834, 1936 (Box 157, Folder 3704)
  - Bank statements: Banca d'America e d'Italia, 1950-58 (Box 157, Folder 3705)
  - PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Calendars, 1983-86 (Box 157, Folder 3706)
    - L'Indice, 1930-31 (Box 157, Folder 3707)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1958-64 (Box 157, Folder 3708)
    - Travel Brochures, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3709)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3710)
  - NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS
    - Fascism / World War II, 1934-73 (Box 158, Folder 3711)
    - Human interest - Jewish Question, 1946-76 (Box 158, Folder 3712)
    - Pound, Ezra
      - Biographical profiles, 1958-87 (Box 158, Folder 3713)
      - Book reviews, 1966-86 (Box 158, Folder 3714)
      - News Photographs - Scrapbook, 1958-74 (Box 158, Folder 3715)
    - Theater - Unidentified, 1966-84 (Box 158, Folder 3716)
  - MUSIC
    - Posters, 1983, n.d. (Box 158, Folder 3717)
    - Printed material, 1937-61 (Box 158, Folder 3718)
    - Scores
      Antheil, George
      - Sonata for Solo Violin. Holograph manuscript, signed, annotated by Olga Rudge, 1923 (Box 158, Folder 3719)
      - Sonata for Violin and Fortepiano: for Olga Rudge. Holograph manuscript, signed, annotated, 1923 (Box 158, Folder 3720)
      - Sonata for Violin and Pianoforte. Holograph manuscript, signed, incomplete, 1923 (Box 158, Folder 3721)
      - Troisieme Sonate pour violon et piano: For Mrs. Christian Gross, respectful hommage. Holograph manuscript, signed, annotated, n.d. (Box 158, Folder 3722)
      - Vivaldi, Antonio
      - Concerto in La: Manuscript in the hand of Ezra Pound, with incomplete pages in another hand (Box 159, Folder 3723)
      - Concerto Opus 6, No. 1 in Sol minore per violino solo e Orchestra. Transcribed and arranged by Gerhard Münch. (Box 159, Folder 3724)
      - Sette Sonate per violino e pianoforte, dalle XII Sonate per violino e basso (Op. 2): a cura dell'Instituto di Alta Cultura con la collaborazione dell'Accademia Chigiana Musicale. Arrangements, signed by Julia Perry, of Sonate IV, V, VI, IX, X, XI, and XII. Dedicated and inscribed to Olga Rudge, 1958-59 (Box 159, Folder 3725)
      - Vivaldi, Antonio. Unidentified and incomplete scores in the hand of Ezra Pound, 1938-39, n.d. (Box 159, Folder 3726-29)
      - Vivaldi, Antonio. Miscellaneous and unidentified pages from transcriptions, many marked "Dresde," in the hand of Olga Rudge (Box 160, Folder 3730)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 160, Folder 3731)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts in the hand of Olga Rudge (Box 160, Folder 3732)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts in the hand of others (Box 160, Folder 3733)
      - Heider, Werner. Commission für Stimme (Bariton) und Kammerensemble gedicht von Ezra Pound (1916). Studienpartitur. Frankfurt: Edition Peters No. 8208 (Box 160, Folder 3734)
      - Károly, Hájos. "Mondja Édes kis Baba." Budapest: Rózsavölgyi & Co., c1927
      - Unidentified page
      - Pizzetti, Ildebrando. Sonata in la per pianoforte e violino: a Ernesto Consolo e a Mario Corti. Printed by J. & W. Chester, Ltd., c1920
      - Ravel, Maurice. A Hélène Jourdan- Morhange. Sonate pour Violon et Piano. Paris: Durand & Co., c1927
      - Vivaldi, Antonio. Concerto for solo Violin or Oboe, Strings and Violin. Op. 8, No. 9. Edited by Sidney Beck. The New York Public Library, 1938
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    Ezra Pound
    - Ezra Pound alone, 1904-72, n.d. (Box 160, Folder 3735)
    - Portraits by Bast, 1971 (Box 161, Folder 3736)
    - Ezra Pound with Olga Rudge (Box 161, Folder 3737)
    - Ezra Pound with Olga Rudge and others, 1923-72, n.d.
    - Ezra Pound with others, 1930-72, n.d. (Box 161, Folder 3738)
    - Olga Rudge
      - Olga Rudge alone, 1897-1958, n.d. (Box 161, Folder 3739)
      - Olga Rudge with others, 1918-88, n.d. (Box 161, Folder 3740)
    - Other persons, n.d. (Box 161, Folder 3741)
    - Miscellaneous Photos
      - Portraits of Ezra Pound (Box 161, Folder 3742)
      - Miscellaneous Artwork, n.d. (Box 162, Folder 3743)
      - Unidentified negatives, n.d. (Box 162, Folder 3744)
  - FAMILY PAPERS
    - Rudge Family Album, ca.1895-1920 (Box 162, Folder 3745-48)